<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eng on imdkm</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/eng/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eng on imdkm</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja-jp</language>
    <copyright>imdkm</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/eng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Examining gender (in)equality among four major music festivals in Japan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-08-17-examining-gender-inequality-among-four-major-music-festivals-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-08-17-examining-gender-inequality-among-four-major-music-festivals-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>In February 2018, PRS Foundation launched a campaign named Keychange. By encouraging music festivals to achieve a 50:50 gender balance by 2022, it aims to make the music industry more inclusive and create a better future. Initially, their partners were 45 festivals around the world but now they include more than 130 festivals.&#xA;Nowadays, music festivals are the industry&amp;rsquo;s most important opportunity to reach a major audience. Moreover, as some big festivals started to stream their stages via YouTube, music festivals became not only a place for the live experience but also a crucial platform of the business.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People In The Box, Kodomo Rengou (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-06-05-people-in-the-box-kodomo-rengou-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-06-05-people-in-the-box-kodomo-rengou-2018/</guid>
      <description>Honestly, I had very little knowledge about People In The Box until their latest Kodomo Rengou, which was released in February 2018. I was relatively new to today&amp;rsquo;s Japanese rock music &amp;lsquo;cuz I was crazy in dance music since the late &amp;rsquo;00s. However, one of my friends strongly recommended the album, saying that it would be the album of the year. Then I tried listening and soon fell in love with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ぼくのりりっくのぼうよみ (Bokunoririkkunobouyomi), 没落 (Botsuraku) (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-28-%E3%81%BC%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%82%8A%E3%82%8A%E3%81%A3%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%81%BC%E3%81%86%E3%82%88%E3%81%BF-%E6%B2%A1%E8%90%BD-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-28-%E3%81%BC%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%82%8A%E3%82%8A%E3%81%A3%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%81%BC%E3%81%86%E3%82%88%E3%81%BF-%E6%B2%A1%E8%90%BD-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=D3L5rARXSRSmODgJxsvt3A&#xD;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post last Wednesday because I was too busy and tired. One of my distraction then was preparing my dj set at Gampeki Music Festival which would be held at the weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ve almost quit djing years ago and my skill is not great at all tho, I enjoyed playing. You can hear it on mixcloud.&#xA;Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to write about ぼくのりりっくのぼうよみ (boku no ririkku no bo&amp;rsquo;yomi, ぼくりり in short)&amp;rsquo;s 没落 (botsuraku).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>江沼郁弥 (ENUMA Fumiya), #1 (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-15-%E6%B1%9F%E6%B2%BC%E9%83%81%E5%BC%A5-1-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-15-%E6%B1%9F%E6%B2%BC%E9%83%81%E5%BC%A5-1-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=DkYFLWLfTrCojM-I6lu9Qw&#xD;Enuma Fumiya&amp;rsquo;s #1 is his first full-length as a solo singer-songwriter. After the break-up of plenty in 2017, the introspective frontman of the band took some synths and a daw into his hands instead of the guitar. While plenty&amp;rsquo;s music was characterized by the shoegaze-like guitar noise with catchy melodies&amp;ndash;say, very &amp;ldquo;indie&amp;rdquo; in a sense&amp;ndash;the album was completely rid of such catharsis. It was like something between psychedelic folk and alternative r&amp;amp;b which could be compared to James Blake&amp;rsquo;s or Frank Ocean&amp;rsquo;s seminal works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tempalay, なんて素晴らしき世界 (Nante Subarashiki Sekai), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-07-tempalay-%E3%81%AA%E3%82%93%E3%81%A6%E7%B4%A0%E6%99%B4%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%8D%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-07-tempalay-%E3%81%AA%E3%82%93%E3%81%A6%E7%B4%A0%E6%99%B4%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%8D%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=4jnQf9N5RCCpUnaPvW2FgA&#xD;When I found that RM (from BTS) was listening to Tempalay&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;どうしよう (dooshiyou)&amp;rdquo; I was very excited since it was one of my most favorite songs then. The song starts with slightly out-of-scale riffs which have a dislocating feeling. After a sudden glitchy edit, the band&amp;rsquo;s vocalist Ryoto Obara begins to sing with the mesmerizing guitar and the bold beat, embraced by their multi-instrumentalist AAAMYYY&amp;rsquo;s backing chorus. I was not satisfied with the cheesy vid but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help watching it over and over and over.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shohei Amimori and the Bacteria Collective&#39;s show was pretty awesome. why don&#39;t you invite them to play?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-24-shohei-amimori-and-the-bacteria-collectives-show-was-pretty-awesome-why-dont-you-invite-them-to-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-24-shohei-amimori-and-the-bacteria-collectives-show-was-pretty-awesome-why-dont-you-invite-them-to-play/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was at Shibuya WWWX to see Shohei Amimori&amp;rsquo;s show called &amp;ldquo;パタミュージッキング (patamusicking)&amp;rdquo; which was the release party for his 2018 album パタミュージック. The support acts, Kasanegi Wrist-band and Takuro Okada were both pretty awesome though, the most impressive act was, of course, the main one&amp;ndash;Shohei Amimori and the Bacteria Collective.&#xA;They were gathered by Amimori to play the songs from the album which has very DAW-oriented post-production and sound processing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perfume, Future Pop (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-16-perfume-future-pop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-16-perfume-future-pop-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=\_VtbN7KdRRq6dPqejd\_SVQ&#xD;Since their breakthrough &amp;ldquo;ポリリズム (polyrhythm)&amp;rdquo; in 2007, Perfume has grown up from a &amp;ldquo;kawaii&amp;rdquo; futuristic electro-pop idol to one of Japan&amp;rsquo;s most popular and fascinating pop act. They just made their first major appearance at Coachella last weekend and highly appreciated (even Rolling Stone named them as one of the best acts at Coachella). It seems that their performance in the second weekend will be streamed via YouTube. It&amp;rsquo;ll be worth watching for their performance will show you the sophisticated side of J-POP: the ensemble of their spontaneous charm, skillful choreography by MIKIKO, and cutting-edge tech effects by Rhizomatics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kid Fresino, ài qing (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-10-kid-fresino-ai-qing-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-10-kid-fresino-ai-qing-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=CtOe2pwdQAW3AF\_XNCF0Bg&#xD;While Asian-American hip-hop collective 88rising&amp;rsquo;s making a viral sensation around the world and K-POP acts like BTS or BLACKPINK are going into the U.S. market with hip-hop oriented imagery, the underground hip-hop scenes around Eastern Asia has been quite interesting for years. Throughout several cities in Japan, maybe especially Tokyo, the new generation of hip-hop acts is emerging and changing the game.&#xA;Kid Fresino began his career as a producer and DJ for hip-hop group Fla$hBacks in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sub-bass, anxiety, and hugs: some notes on therapeutic values of Billie Eilish&#39;s music</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-05-sub-bass-anxiety-and-hugs-some-notes-on-therapeutic-values-of-billie-eilishs-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-05-sub-bass-anxiety-and-hugs-some-notes-on-therapeutic-values-of-billie-eilishs-music/</guid>
      <description>?si=eV6kRwwFSNCtVHM\_ICdCMQ&#xD;As you can see it on the billboard hot 100 charts, Billie Eilish&amp;rsquo;s debut When We All Fall Asleep, Where Do We Go? is making fascination among young listeners in the States. Many Japanese listeners are also fascinated by the album and Eilish&amp;rsquo;s charismatic behavior, and I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid to say I&amp;rsquo;m the one. I&amp;rsquo;m completely crazy in her.&#xA;Today I read an interesting article which features Eilish&amp;rsquo;s interview. It was &amp;ldquo;Billie Eilish’s Teenage Truths: How the unfiltered 17-year-old singer with dark visions became pop’s new conscience&amp;rdquo; by Jonah Weiner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You gotta check &#34;Apple Vinegar Music Award&#34;, the musicians&#39; choice of the year.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-02-you-gotta-check-apple-vinegar-music-award-the-musicians-choice-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-02-you-gotta-check-apple-vinegar-music-award-the-musicians-choice-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Hm. Hi, this is imdkm. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted nine entries since January. I dunno how many people reading this blog, but I hope someday these entries would be read by many music fans and make &amp;rsquo;em listen to Japanese pop music more. This year&amp;rsquo;s resolution of mine.&#xA;Well, today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce an interesting project named &amp;ldquo;Apple Vinegar Music Award&amp;rdquo;. It is an independent annual award to shed the light on the year&amp;rsquo;s most excellent but relatively unknown releases of young musicians in Japan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maison book girl, yume, 2018.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-27-maison-book-girl-yume-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-27-maison-book-girl-yume-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=cwc8RUsnS\_qMYFN22aDXGg&#xD;In Japan, there has been a so-called &amp;ldquo;idol&amp;rdquo; scene for decades. Yes, you may know Perfume, BABYMETAL, and several groups which feature young female performers. But there are much more to check out. Maison book girl is one of them. They&amp;rsquo;re my most favorite group, and their 2018 full-length yume is a masterpiece (IMO).&#xA;Before introducing the album, let me roughly trace a brief history of recent idol scene in Japan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tofubeats, RUN, 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-20-tofubeats-run-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-20-tofubeats-run-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=0dzgUv-7S1OEOyyqiNcAhQ&#xD;The 2010s was the decade of tofubeats. Some wouldn&amp;rsquo;t agree with me but this has been my honest feeling for years. Working with numerous J-POP acts like Chisato Moritaka, KREVA, Bonnie Pink etc., now he is one of the most popular DJ and producer among his generation. &amp;ldquo;水星&amp;rdquo;, his earliest breakthrough hit, is like the decade&amp;rsquo;s standard number as many young pop singers have made their own version of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>長谷川白紙 (Hakushi Hasegawa), 草木萌動 (So-moku Ho-do), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-13-%E9%95%B7%E8%B0%B7%E5%B7%9D%E7%99%BD%E7%B4%99-hakushi-hasegawa-%E8%8D%89%E6%9C%A8%E8%90%8C%E5%8B%95-so-moku-ho-do-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-13-%E9%95%B7%E8%B0%B7%E5%B7%9D%E7%99%BD%E7%B4%99-hakushi-hasegawa-%E8%8D%89%E6%9C%A8%E8%90%8C%E5%8B%95-so-moku-ho-do-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=mjywd9IGRV2gT0nG2oMK7Q&#xD;There has been a so-called &amp;ldquo;netlabel&amp;rdquo; scene in Japan since the late 2000s as well as overseas. Maltine Records is one of the most famous netlabels in Japan, which was founded by two then high school students in 2005. Specializing in the contemporary dance and electronic music producers, they&amp;rsquo;ve released over 170 singles or eps including ones by dj newtown (a.k.a. tofubeats), TORIENA, Pa&amp;rsquo;s Lam System, パソコン音楽クラブ (Pasocom Ongaku Club) etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>三浦大知 (Daichi Miura), 球体 (Kyu-tai), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-06-%E4%B8%89%E6%B5%A6%E5%A4%A7%E7%9F%A5-daichi-miura-%E7%90%83%E4%BD%93-kyu-tai-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-06-%E4%B8%89%E6%B5%A6%E5%A4%A7%E7%9F%A5-daichi-miura-%E7%90%83%E4%BD%93-kyu-tai-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=kDjUDBd4S9aSWnrz6ZXPxw&#xD;Kiyoshi Matsuo, the R&amp;amp;B expert and renowned producer, once said that Japanese people prefer a genuine singer to an all-rounder. Eiichi Ohtaki, the legendary singer and songwriter, also pointed out that Japanese people tend to value singing too much. In Japan, it can be said that an ideal singer must sing emotionally without moving so the audience can absorb into the voice.&#xA;However, Daichi Miura&amp;rsquo;s distinguished performance would change such unconscious bias among Japanese people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cero, POLY LIFE MULTI SOUL, 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-27-cero-poly-life-multi-soul-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-27-cero-poly-life-multi-soul-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=A5dELjYlS3u93Lpx17LlQg&#xD;Throughout the 2010s, Japanese pop music has been obsessed with the so-called &amp;lsquo;urban&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;city&amp;rsquo; feeling. Many bands tried to render their impressions on their own city life, mostly in Tokyo. They sounded more optimistic than how the society actually was, but I think it was kinda redevelopment of their imaginary city. After the great earthquake in 2011, this act of redevelopment became more crucial since the city&amp;ndash;well, of course, Tokyo&amp;ndash;was heavily damaged both literally and psychologically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>中村佳穂 (Kaho Nakamura), AINOU, 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-20-kaho-nakamura-ainou-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-20-kaho-nakamura-ainou-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=wH-vyZIIR9OQOzE4qFspaw&#xD;Kyoto, the ancient capital of Japan, is known for its cultural scenes. Regarding music, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of musicians playing indie rock, electronic music, hip hop, and more eclectic things. This is maybe because of the nature of the city, where is known as students&amp;rsquo; city with lots of universities in rather a small area. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also precious historical heritage making this town enchanted.&#xA;Kaho Nakamura is a Kyoto-native singer and songwriter, and is one of the most prominent figures in recent Kyoto cultural scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>崎山蒼志 (Sohshi Sakiyama), いつかみた国 (Itsuka Mita Kuni), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-13-sohshi-sakiyama-%E3%81%84%E3%81%A4%E3%81%8B%E3%81%BF%E3%81%9F%E5%9B%BD-itsuka-mita-kuni-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-13-sohshi-sakiyama-%E3%81%84%E3%81%A4%E3%81%8B%E3%81%BF%E3%81%9F%E5%9B%BD-itsuka-mita-kuni-2018/</guid>
      <description>?si=2jeQ-iQcSGOdImXG\_s91tg&#xD;Sohshi Sakiyama is a singer and songwriter from Hamamatsu, Shizuoka. He&amp;rsquo;s only 16-year-old but has gained enormous attention throughout 2018, since he appeared on AbemaTV&amp;rsquo;s program &amp;ldquo;日村が行く！(Himura ga Yuku)&amp;rdquo;, where he played his song &amp;ldquo;五月雨 (Samidare)&amp;rdquo;. The video went viral as soon as it appeared on Twitter and quickly built a huge fan base among the listeners including well-known Japanese rock musicians such as Enon Kawatani (from Gesu no Kiwami Otome), or Shigeru Kishida (from Quruli).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>宇多田ヒカル (Hikaru Utada), 初恋(Hatsukoi), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-04-hikaru-utada-%E5%88%9D%E6%81%8Bhatsukoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-04-hikaru-utada-%E5%88%9D%E6%81%8Bhatsukoi/</guid>
      <description>?si=96qWSGFOSsG1\_K4ZWTZ94g&#xD;If you&amp;rsquo;re acquainted with the Japanese pop culture, you may know Hikaru Utada. She&amp;rsquo;s one of Japan&amp;rsquo;s most famous singer and songwriter in these decades. Her debut album First Love sold over 10 million copies worldwide. It is the best selling J-POP album in history&amp;ndash;and no one will ever break this record.&#xA;In 1998, with her debut single &amp;ldquo;Automatic / time will tell,&amp;rdquo; she changed the entire landscape of J-POP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>折坂悠太 (Yuta Orisaka), 平成 (Heisei), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-01-30-yuta-orisaka-heisei-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-01-30-yuta-orisaka-heisei-2018/</guid>
      <description>Heisei era, beginning in early 1989 as Emperor Hirohito deceased, is going to end in April 2019. It was the era of increasing depression both economically and socially. These three decades are known notoriously as &amp;ldquo;lost decades,&amp;rdquo; Japanese people went through the collapse of the economy and severe disasters like several great earthquakes, ane even faced the fear of terrorism by some religious cults.&#xA;Yuta Orisaka was born in 1989.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly Life Multi Soulのリズムメモ</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2018-05-20-2018-05-20-234632/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2018-05-20-2018-05-20-234632/</guid>
      <description>夕方書いた記事の補足。&#xA;POLY LIFE MULTI SOUL (通常盤)&#xA;アーティスト: cero 出版社/メーカー: カクバリズム 発売日: 2018/05/16 メディア: CD この商品を含むブログを見る さいしょに パルス リズムの基礎単位 拍子 一小節を何分割しているかの単位 メトリック・モジュレーション パルスの長さを維持しながら拍子を伸縮させる ●=○=1パルス、●=アクセント、○=休符とした場合、 A:｜●○○○●○○○●○○○●○○○｜●○○○●○○○… B:｜●○○●○○●○○●○○｜●○○●○○●○○●○○… AとBはパルスの長さを共有しているが小節の長さ（＝実質的なテンポ）が異なる。 よくあるパターンとしては、付点音符を使ったシンコペーションを使って小節をまたいで拍子をスムースに変化させる例 クロスリズム 複数の拍子に解釈可能な単一のリズム・パターン 小節あたりのパルスの数が公倍数になっているときに可能 典型的なのはパルスの数が12の場合のクロスリズム ｜●○○●○○●○○●○○｜(四分三連の4/4もしくは12/8) ｜●○○○●○○○●○○○｜(3/4) 12/8もしくは3/4の場合、基本的にすべてクロスリズムとして解釈できるが、実際にはアクセントの位置やメロディの流れによってどちらかに一意に決まることが多い。 ポリリズム ひとつの小節のなかに異なる複数の拍子が共存している 4/4のリズムの上に三連がのっている、etc&amp;hellip; 最近流行りの三連フロウもポリリズムっちゃポリリズム。&#xA;パルスは共有しているが小節の長さが異なる Perfume - ポリリズムにおけるポリリズムパート 三拍子のうえで5音節の単語をくり返して小節がまわりこんだり揃ったりをくり返す。&#xA;どちらもポリリズム…　だと思う 各曲メモ（気になったのだけ） Modern Steps メトリック・モジュレーションを使ったリズムチェンジ イントロのギターとオルガンは4/4（その後のパートとはテンポが異なる） リズムボックスが入ってからは[4/4 *2 + 5/4 * 2] * 3（1パルス＝八分音符として、1周期36パルス） 四分三連の3/4に移行（1周期18パルス） 最後のギターは7/8 + 11/8（1周期18パルス） 魚の骨　鳥の羽根 3と4のクロスリズム キメの部分でどちらかの拍子が優勢に聞こえる部分もあるが、全体を通して3にも4にもとれるきれいなクロスリズム ベッテン・フォールズ メトリック・モジュレーションを使ったリズムチェンジがばんばん 5/4→9/8→12/8→5/4→9/8→4/4→12/8…［20220228 いま思うと5/4は10/8と書いたほうがいい］ 溯行 後半に4/4から12/8へのメトリック・モジュレーション Buzzle Bee Ride 一貫して7/4だが、クラーベがわりのベルが抜けた後半に激しいシンコペーションがある。 Double Exposure 4/4。ただし3小節を1周期として進行するのでちょっとだけ変則的に聞こえる。 Waters 3/4。中盤で一部周期が倍になって6/4。 要所要所でクロスリズム的にとれ、後半でシンセのコードだけになるところ以降ははっきりとクロスリズム的なパターン。 以上です </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
