<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eng on imdkm</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/eng/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eng on imdkm</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja-jp</language>
    <copyright>imdkm</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/eng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Examining gender (in)equality among four major music festivals in Japan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-08-17-examining-gender-inequality-among-four-major-music-festivals-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-08-17-examining-gender-inequality-among-four-major-music-festivals-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2018, PRS Foundation launched a campaign named &lt;a href=&#34;https://keychange.eu/&#34;&gt;Keychange&lt;/a&gt;. By encouraging music festivals to achieve a 50:50 gender balance by 2022, it aims to make the music industry more inclusive and create a better future. Initially, their partners were 45 festivals around the world but now they include more than 130 festivals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, music festivals are the industry&amp;rsquo;s most important opportunity to reach a major audience. Moreover, as some big festivals started to stream their stages via YouTube, music festivals became not only a place for the live experience but also a crucial platform of the business. So Keychange&amp;rsquo;s activity is to the point. Festivals could epitomize the whole industry in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People In The Box, Kodomo Rengou (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-06-05-people-in-the-box-kodomo-rengou-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-06-05-people-in-the-box-kodomo-rengou-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I had very little knowledge about People In The Box until their latest &lt;em&gt;Kodomo Rengou&lt;/em&gt;, which was released in February 2018. I was relatively new to today&amp;rsquo;s Japanese rock music &amp;lsquo;cuz I was crazy in dance music since the late &amp;rsquo;00s. However, one of my friends strongly recommended the album, saying that it would be the album of the year. Then I tried listening and soon fell in love with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to it over and over, even ignoring other new releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ぼくのりりっくのぼうよみ (Bokunoririkkunobouyomi), 没落 (Botsuraku) (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-28-%E3%81%BC%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%82%8A%E3%82%8A%E3%81%A3%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%81%BC%E3%81%86%E3%82%88%E3%81%BF-%E6%B2%A1%E8%90%BD-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-28-%E3%81%BC%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%82%8A%E3%82%8A%E3%81%A3%E3%81%8F%E3%81%AE%E3%81%BC%E3%81%86%E3%82%88%E3%81%BF-%E6%B2%A1%E8%90%BD-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/5MSPC7Nwd079uK2YyN6Gh8&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=D3L5rARXSRSmODgJxsvt3A&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post last Wednesday because I was too busy and tired. One of my distraction then was preparing my dj set at Gampeki Music Festival which would be held at the weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ve almost quit djing years ago and my skill is not great at all tho, I enjoyed playing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mixcloud.com/imdkm/imdkm-gampeki-music-fes-2019-05-25/&#34;&gt;You can hear it on mixcloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to write about ぼくのりりっくのぼうよみ (boku no ririkku no bo&amp;rsquo;yomi, ぼくりり in short)&amp;rsquo;s 没落 (botsuraku). The title means &amp;ldquo;fall&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;decay&amp;rdquo; literally. It was his last album under the name ぼくのりりっくのぼうよみ. He was a young and talented singer and songwriter with a unique voice and thoughtful lyrics, whose music attracted the wide audience. His dance-oriented beat and eloquent vocalization were mellow and youthful at the same time, no other singers had a charismatic atmosphere as his one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>江沼郁弥 (ENUMA Fumiya), #1 (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-15-%E6%B1%9F%E6%B2%BC%E9%83%81%E5%BC%A5-1-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-15-%E6%B1%9F%E6%B2%BC%E9%83%81%E5%BC%A5-1-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/1THXec52uSoXkXNJvMLUNy&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=DkYFLWLfTrCojM-I6lu9Qw&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enuma Fumiya&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;#1&lt;/em&gt; is his first full-length as a solo singer-songwriter. After the break-up of plenty in 2017, the introspective frontman of the band took some synths and a daw into his hands instead of the guitar. While plenty&amp;rsquo;s music was characterized by the shoegaze-like guitar noise with catchy melodies&amp;ndash;say, very &amp;ldquo;indie&amp;rdquo; in a sense&amp;ndash;the album was completely rid of such catharsis. It was like something between psychedelic folk and alternative r&amp;amp;b which could be compared to James Blake&amp;rsquo;s or Frank Ocean&amp;rsquo;s seminal works. I would say that he was finding another way to express his thought with a great delicacy. And he actually did it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tempalay, なんて素晴らしき世界 (Nante Subarashiki Sekai), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-07-tempalay-%E3%81%AA%E3%82%93%E3%81%A6%E7%B4%A0%E6%99%B4%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%8D%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-05-07-tempalay-%E3%81%AA%E3%82%93%E3%81%A6%E7%B4%A0%E6%99%B4%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%8D%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/44sckHW5kHPrlFjffVzkI4&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=4jnQf9N5RCCpUnaPvW2FgA&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I found that RM (from BTS) was listening to Tempalay&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;どうしよう (dooshiyou)&amp;rdquo; I was very excited since it was one of my most favorite songs then. The song starts with slightly out-of-scale riffs which have a dislocating feeling. After a sudden glitchy edit, the band&amp;rsquo;s vocalist Ryoto Obara begins to sing with the mesmerizing guitar and the bold beat, embraced by their multi-instrumentalist AAAMYYY&amp;rsquo;s backing chorus. I was not satisfied with the cheesy vid but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help watching it over and over and over. I thought RM might feel the same way as me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shohei Amimori and the Bacteria Collective&#39;s show was pretty awesome. why don&#39;t you invite them to play?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-24-shohei-amimori-and-the-bacteria-collectives-show-was-pretty-awesome-why-dont-you-invite-them-to-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-24-shohei-amimori-and-the-bacteria-collectives-show-was-pretty-awesome-why-dont-you-invite-them-to-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I was at Shibuya WWWX to see Shohei Amimori&amp;rsquo;s show called &amp;ldquo;パタミュージッキング (patamusicking)&amp;rdquo; which was the release party for his 2018 album パタミュージック. The support acts, Kasanegi Wrist-band and Takuro Okada were both pretty awesome though, the most impressive act was, of course, the main one&amp;ndash;Shohei Amimori and the Bacteria Collective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They were gathered by Amimori to play the songs from the album which has very DAW-oriented post-production and sound processing. So I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how it would be, even a little bit suspicious about that. Deliberately composed and edited, they have quite complex structures and it seemed to be almost impossible to play them live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perfume, Future Pop (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-16-perfume-future-pop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-16-perfume-future-pop-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/0e7AS0Cgn03lXq2orBHQG0&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=\_VtbN7KdRRq6dPqejd\_SVQ&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since their breakthrough &amp;ldquo;ポリリズム (polyrhythm)&amp;rdquo; in 2007, Perfume has grown up from a &amp;ldquo;kawaii&amp;rdquo; futuristic electro-pop idol to one of Japan&amp;rsquo;s most popular and fascinating pop act. They just made their first major appearance at Coachella last weekend and highly appreciated (even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-lists/coachella-2019-best-performances-ariana-grande-nsync-822246/&#34;&gt;Rolling Stone named them as one of the best acts at Coachella&lt;/a&gt;). It seems that their performance in the second weekend will be streamed via YouTube. It&amp;rsquo;ll be worth watching for their performance will show you the sophisticated side of J-POP: the ensemble of their spontaneous charm, skillful choreography by MIKIKO, and cutting-edge tech effects by Rhizomatics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kid Fresino, ài qing (2018)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-10-kid-fresino-ai-qing-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-10-kid-fresino-ai-qing-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/7qMgzRK8TKUbyECfMY9GGr&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=CtOe2pwdQAW3AF\_XNCF0Bg&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While Asian-American hip-hop collective 88rising&amp;rsquo;s making a viral sensation around the world and K-POP acts like BTS or BLACKPINK are going into the U.S. market with hip-hop oriented imagery, the underground hip-hop scenes around Eastern Asia has been quite interesting for years. Throughout several cities in Japan, maybe especially Tokyo, the new generation of hip-hop acts is emerging and changing the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kid Fresino began his career as a producer and DJ for hip-hop group Fla$hBacks in 2013. Soon he also started to rap and released his own solo works in parallel with the group. Switching Japanese and English alternately, he spits verses in a sticky, slightly off-the-pocket but groovy manner. He&amp;rsquo;s been known for being prolific as both producer and rapper (lots of guest appearances and collaboration such as &lt;em&gt;Somewhere&lt;/em&gt;, a double name album with the Nagoya-based rapper C.O.S.A.) but since returning to Japan from a few years stay in NY he turned his direction a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sub-bass, anxiety, and hugs: some notes on therapeutic values of Billie Eilish&#39;s music</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-05-sub-bass-anxiety-and-hugs-some-notes-on-therapeutic-values-of-billie-eilishs-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-05-sub-bass-anxiety-and-hugs-some-notes-on-therapeutic-values-of-billie-eilishs-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/0S0KGZnfBGSIssfF54WSJh&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=eV6kRwwFSNCtVHM\_ICdCMQ&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see it on the billboard hot 100 charts, Billie Eilish&amp;rsquo;s debut &lt;em&gt;When We All Fall Asleep, Where Do We Go?&lt;/em&gt; is making fascination among young listeners in the States. Many Japanese listeners are also fascinated by the album and Eilish&amp;rsquo;s charismatic behavior, and I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid to say I&amp;rsquo;m the one. I&amp;rsquo;m completely crazy in her.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DyDfgMOUjCI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I read an interesting article which features Eilish&amp;rsquo;s interview. It was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/billie-eilish-album-songs-interview-tour-tickets-797040/&#34;&gt;Billie Eilish’s Teenage Truths: How the unfiltered 17-year-old singer with dark visions became pop’s new conscience&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Jonah Weiner. But the Japanese version of the article had a different title that said &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rollingstonejapan.com/articles/detail/30460&#34;&gt;若い子たちにとって私の曲はハグなの (Kids use my songs as a hug.)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; quoting her words. This quote impressed me because calling her music &amp;ldquo;a hug&amp;rdquo; seemed to be quite accurate to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You gotta check &#34;Apple Vinegar Music Award&#34;, the musicians&#39; choice of the year.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-02-you-gotta-check-apple-vinegar-music-award-the-musicians-choice-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-04-02-you-gotta-check-apple-vinegar-music-award-the-musicians-choice-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hm. Hi, this is imdkm. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted nine entries since January. I dunno how many people reading this blog, but I hope someday these entries would be read by many music fans and make &amp;rsquo;em listen to Japanese pop music more. This year&amp;rsquo;s resolution of mine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce an interesting project named &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.applevinegarmusicaward.com/&#34;&gt;Apple Vinegar Music Award&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. It is an independent annual award to shed the light on the year&amp;rsquo;s most excellent but relatively unknown releases of young musicians in Japan. It was founded by Masafumi Goto, who is ASIAN KUNG-FU GENERATION&amp;rsquo;s vocalist and guitarist, in 2018 (for those who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know &amp;rsquo;em, the band&amp;rsquo;s introduction is in the final paragraphs of this post). Nominees are selected by him and judges are well-known musicians in J-POP scene, who are friends of him&amp;ndash;seemingly rather private than public, but its mission is very ambitious for just an personal project. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s worth to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maison book girl, yume, 2018.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-27-maison-book-girl-yume-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-27-maison-book-girl-yume-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/4oiCS2mJi94pmj9aypPEOz&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=cwc8RUsnS\_qMYFN22aDXGg&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Japan, there has been a so-called &amp;ldquo;idol&amp;rdquo; scene for decades. Yes, you may know Perfume, BABYMETAL, and several groups which feature young female performers. But there are much more to check out. Maison book girl is one of them. They&amp;rsquo;re my most favorite group, and their 2018 full-length &lt;em&gt;yume&lt;/em&gt; is a masterpiece (IMO).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before introducing the album, let me roughly trace a brief history of recent idol scene in Japan. Since AKB48&amp;rsquo;s debut in 2005, numerous girls&amp;rsquo; groups have emerged both overground and underground. The latter ones were called &amp;ldquo;地下アイドル (Chika Idol)&amp;rdquo; and established its cultural status in Japanese pop culture. Today the line between major idols and underground idols have been blurred and the entire idol scene is getting saturated. But some acts continue to endeavor to make more unique, sophisticated works and performances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tofubeats, RUN, 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-20-tofubeats-run-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-20-tofubeats-run-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/768w3G6KlQfsegNgMm3XG1&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=0dzgUv-7S1OEOyyqiNcAhQ&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 2010s was the decade of tofubeats. Some wouldn&amp;rsquo;t agree with me but this has been my honest feeling for years. Working with numerous J-POP acts like Chisato Moritaka, KREVA, Bonnie Pink etc., now he is one of the most popular DJ and producer among his generation. &amp;ldquo;水星&amp;rdquo;, his earliest breakthrough hit, is like the decade&amp;rsquo;s standard number as many young pop singers have made their own version of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>長谷川白紙 (Hakushi Hasegawa), 草木萌動 (So-moku Ho-do), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-13-%E9%95%B7%E8%B0%B7%E5%B7%9D%E7%99%BD%E7%B4%99-hakushi-hasegawa-%E8%8D%89%E6%9C%A8%E8%90%8C%E5%8B%95-so-moku-ho-do-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-13-%E9%95%B7%E8%B0%B7%E5%B7%9D%E7%99%BD%E7%B4%99-hakushi-hasegawa-%E8%8D%89%E6%9C%A8%E8%90%8C%E5%8B%95-so-moku-ho-do-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/5D0i8bR94UAccdT51l4v06&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=mjywd9IGRV2gT0nG2oMK7Q&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been a so-called &amp;ldquo;netlabel&amp;rdquo; scene in Japan since the late 2000s as well as overseas. &lt;a href=&#34;http://maltinerecords.cs8.biz/&#34;&gt;Maltine Records&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most famous netlabels in Japan, which was founded by two then high school students in 2005. Specializing in the contemporary dance and electronic music producers, they&amp;rsquo;ve released over 170 singles or eps including ones by dj newtown (a.k.a. tofubeats), TORIENA, Pa&amp;rsquo;s Lam System, パソコン音楽クラブ (Pasocom Ongaku Club) etc..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>三浦大知 (Daichi Miura), 球体 (Kyu-tai), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-06-%E4%B8%89%E6%B5%A6%E5%A4%A7%E7%9F%A5-daichi-miura-%E7%90%83%E4%BD%93-kyu-tai-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-03-06-%E4%B8%89%E6%B5%A6%E5%A4%A7%E7%9F%A5-daichi-miura-%E7%90%83%E4%BD%93-kyu-tai-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/0sG5eHkkoCNcpqH4gyneBX&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=kDjUDBd4S9aSWnrz6ZXPxw&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kiyoshi Matsuo, the R&amp;amp;B expert and renowned producer, once said that Japanese people prefer a genuine singer to an all-rounder. Eiichi Ohtaki, the legendary singer and songwriter, also pointed out that Japanese people tend to value singing too much. In Japan, it can be said that an ideal singer must sing emotionally without moving so the audience can absorb into the voice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, Daichi Miura&amp;rsquo;s distinguished performance would change such unconscious bias among Japanese people. He&amp;rsquo;s undoubtedly the most acclaimed pop act in Japan now, and his latest full-length &lt;em&gt;球体&lt;/em&gt; gained so much attention that some critics and listeners concidered the album as the best release in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cero, POLY LIFE MULTI SOUL, 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-27-cero-poly-life-multi-soul-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-27-cero-poly-life-multi-soul-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/6JD9GiACPTf4symuPbpfPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=A5dELjYlS3u93Lpx17LlQg&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the 2010s, Japanese pop music has been obsessed with the so-called &amp;lsquo;urban&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;city&amp;rsquo; feeling. Many bands tried to render their impressions on their own city life, mostly in Tokyo. They sounded more optimistic than how the society actually was, but I think it was kinda redevelopment of their imaginary city. After the great earthquake in 2011, this act of redevelopment became more crucial since the city&amp;ndash;well, of course, Tokyo&amp;ndash;was heavily damaged both literally and psychologically. They needed to fix it, at least imaginarily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>中村佳穂 (Kaho Nakamura), AINOU, 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-20-kaho-nakamura-ainou-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-20-kaho-nakamura-ainou-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/6OfjyI10e9vEFFzWdcmwqW&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=wH-vyZIIR9OQOzE4qFspaw&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyoto, the ancient capital of Japan, is known for its cultural scenes. Regarding music, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of musicians playing indie rock, electronic music, hip hop, and more eclectic things. This is maybe because of the nature of the city, where is known as students&amp;rsquo; city with lots of universities in rather a small area. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also precious historical heritage making this town enchanted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kaho Nakamura is a Kyoto-native singer and songwriter, and is one of the most prominent figures in recent Kyoto cultural scene. Her second full-length &lt;em&gt;AINOU&lt;/em&gt; was critically acclaimed for its distinguished composition, sound design, and excellent vocalization. Praised by senior musicians like Kan Takano, Shigeru Kishida, and tofubeats, she was already known for her playful performance which was full of virtuosity. However, the album was the real breakthrough for her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>崎山蒼志 (Sohshi Sakiyama), いつかみた国 (Itsuka Mita Kuni), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-13-sohshi-sakiyama-%E3%81%84%E3%81%A4%E3%81%8B%E3%81%BF%E3%81%9F%E5%9B%BD-itsuka-mita-kuni-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-13-sohshi-sakiyama-%E3%81%84%E3%81%A4%E3%81%8B%E3%81%BF%E3%81%9F%E5%9B%BD-itsuka-mita-kuni-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/4EM4fTaRgbM0EMOGF0NGle&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=2jeQ-iQcSGOdImXG\_s91tg&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sohshi Sakiyama is a singer and songwriter from Hamamatsu, Shizuoka. He&amp;rsquo;s only 16-year-old but has gained enormous attention throughout 2018, since he appeared on AbemaTV&amp;rsquo;s program &amp;ldquo;日村が行く！(Himura ga Yuku)&amp;rdquo;, where he played his song &amp;ldquo;五月雨 (Samidare)&amp;rdquo;. The video went viral as soon as it appeared on Twitter and quickly built a huge fan base among the listeners including well-known Japanese rock musicians such as Enon Kawatani (from Gesu no Kiwami Otome), or Shigeru Kishida (from Quruli).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>宇多田ヒカル (Hikaru Utada), 初恋(Hatsukoi), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-04-hikaru-utada-%E5%88%9D%E6%81%8Bhatsukoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-02-04-hikaru-utada-%E5%88%9D%E6%81%8Bhatsukoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/5ejvTc5RFRnM6MrczQxzTE&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;?si=96qWSGFOSsG1\_K4ZWTZ94g&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re acquainted with the Japanese pop culture, you may know Hikaru Utada. She&amp;rsquo;s one of Japan&amp;rsquo;s most famous singer and songwriter in these decades. Her debut album &lt;em&gt;First Love&lt;/em&gt; sold over 10 million copies worldwide. It is the best selling J-POP album in history&amp;ndash;and no one will ever break this record.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1998, with her debut single &amp;ldquo;Automatic / time will tell,&amp;rdquo; she changed the entire landscape of J-POP. Heavily influenced by the contemporary urban music like R&amp;amp;B, she showed Japanese audience how the Japanese language can groove on the R&amp;amp;B-oriented beat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>折坂悠太 (Yuta Orisaka), 平成 (Heisei), 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-01-30-yuta-orisaka-heisei-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2019-01-30-yuta-orisaka-heisei-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/3yaeDnL81FcAFRxgpOsNah&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heisei era, beginning in early 1989 as Emperor Hirohito deceased, is going to end in April 2019. It was the era of increasing depression both economically and socially. These three decades are known notoriously as &amp;ldquo;lost decades,&amp;rdquo; Japanese people went through the collapse of the economy and severe disasters like several great earthquakes, ane even faced the fear of terrorism by some religious cults.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yuta Orisaka was born in 1989. His life has been therefore along with Heisei era. At the very end of it, perhaps he&amp;rsquo;s inevitably conscious about what these three decades meant to him. So he wrote a song and named it &amp;ldquo;Heisei,&amp;rdquo; moreover he decided to make it the title of the entire album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly Life Multi Soulのリズムメモ</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2018-05-20-2018-05-20-234632/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/old_blog/2018-05-20-2018-05-20-234632/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;夕方書いた記事の補足。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.jp/exec/obidos/ASIN/B07BDNVV55/tortoisetau09-22/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/411%2Bgbo79VL._SL160_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;POLY LIFE MULTI SOUL (通常盤)&#34; title=&#34;POLY LIFE MULTI SOUL (通常盤)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.jp/exec/obidos/ASIN/B07BDNVV55/tortoisetau09-22/&#34;&gt;POLY LIFE MULTI SOUL (通常盤)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;アーティスト: &lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/cero&#34;&gt;cero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;出版社/メーカー: &lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%AB%A5%AF%A5%D0%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;カクバリズム&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;発売日: 2018/05/16&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;メディア: CD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/asin/B07BDNVV55/tortoisetau09-22&#34;&gt;この商品を含むブログを見る&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;さいしょに&#34;&gt;さいしょに&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;パルス&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;リズムの基礎単位&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;拍子&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;一小節を何分割しているかの単位&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;メトリック・&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%E2%A5%B8%A5%E5%A5%EC&#34;&gt;モジュレ&lt;/a&gt;ーション&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;パルスの長さを維持しながら拍子を伸縮させる&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;●=○=1パルス、●=アクセント、○=休符とした場合、&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A:｜●○○○●○○○●○○○●○○○｜●○○○●○○○…&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;B:｜●○○●○○●○○●○○｜●○○●○○●○○●○○…&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AとBはパルスの長さを共有しているが小節の長さ（＝実質的なテンポ）が異なる。&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;よくあるパターンとしては、付点音符を使った&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%B7%A5%F3%A5%B3%A5%DA%A1%BC%A5%B7%A5%E7%A5%F3&#34;&gt;シンコペーション&lt;/a&gt;を使って小節をまたいで拍子をスムースに変化させる例&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;クロスリズム&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;複数の拍子に解釈可能な単一のリズム・パターン&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;小節あたりのパルスの数が公倍数になっているときに可能&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;典型的なのはパルスの数が12の場合のクロスリズム&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;｜●○○●○○●○○●○○｜(四分三連の4/4もしくは12/8)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;｜●○○○●○○○●○○○｜(3/4)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12/8もしくは3/4の場合、基本的にすべてクロスリズムとして解釈できるが、実際にはアクセントの位置やメロディの流れによってどちらかに一意に決まることが多い。&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-WJ0GqWHhII&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%DD%A5%EA%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;ポリリズム&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ひとつの小節のなかに異なる複数の拍子が共存している&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4/4のリズムの上に三連がのっている、etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fGqdIPer-ms&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;最近流行りの三連フロウも&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%DD%A5%EA%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;ポリリズム&lt;/a&gt;っちゃ&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%DD%A5%EA%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;ポリリズム&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;パルスは共有しているが小節の長さが異なる&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/Perfume&#34;&gt;Perfume&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%DD%A5%EA%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;ポリリズム&lt;/a&gt;における&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%DD%A5%EA%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;ポリリズム&lt;/a&gt;パート&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KbiSxunJatM&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;三拍子のうえで5音節の単語をくり返して小節がまわりこんだり揃ったりをくり返す。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;どちらも&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%DD%A5%EA%A5%EA%A5%BA%A5%E0&#34;&gt;ポリリズム&lt;/a&gt;…　だと思う&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;各曲メモ気になったのだけ&#34;&gt;各曲メモ（気になったのだけ）&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Steps&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;メトリック・&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%E2%A5%B8%A5%E5%A5%EC&#34;&gt;モジュレ&lt;/a&gt;ーションを使ったリズムチェンジ&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;イントロのギターとオルガンは4/4（その後のパートとはテンポが異なる）&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;リズムボックスが入ってからは[4/4 *2 + 5/4 * 2] * 3（1パルス＝八分音符として、1周期36パルス）&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;四分三連の3/4に移行（1周期18パルス）&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;最後のギターは7/8 + 11/8（1周期18パルス）&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;魚の骨　鳥の羽根&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3と4のクロスリズム&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;キメの部分でどちらかの拍子が優勢に聞こえる部分もあるが、全体を通して3にも4にもとれるきれいなクロスリズム&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ベッテン・フォールズ&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;メトリック・&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%E2%A5%B8%A5%E5%A5%EC&#34;&gt;モジュレ&lt;/a&gt;ーションを使ったリズムチェンジがばんばん&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5/4→9/8→12/8→5/4→9/8→4/4→12/8…［20220228 いま思うと5/4は10/8と書いたほうがいい］&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;溯行&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;後半に4/4から12/8へのメトリック・&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%E2%A5%B8%A5%E5%A5%EC&#34;&gt;モジュレ&lt;/a&gt;ーション&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/Buzzle&#34;&gt;Buzzle&lt;/a&gt; Bee Ride&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;一貫して7/4だが、クラーベがわりのベルが抜けた後半に激しい&lt;a href=&#34;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/keyword/%A5%B7%A5%F3%A5%B3%A5%DA%A1%BC%A5%B7%A5%E7%A5%F3&#34;&gt;シンコペーション&lt;/a&gt;がある。&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Double Exposure&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4/4。ただし3小節を1周期として進行するのでちょっとだけ変則的に聞こえる。&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Waters&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3/4。中盤で一部周期が倍になって6/4。&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;要所要所でクロスリズム的にとれ、後半でシンセのコードだけになるところ以降ははっきりとクロスリズム的なパターン。&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;以上です&#34;&gt;以上です&lt;/h3&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
